NATHAN BITU DE OLIVEIRA | DATA SCIENTIST

São Bernardo do Campo, SP | +55 (11) 95950-3332 | nathan.bitu@gmail.com

Goal: Data Scientist

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Future computer engineer with 2 years of internship experience in data analysis. Analytical, solution-oriented profile with advanced English and skills in ETL, Data Analysis, and Machine Learning. Work experience with Python, Tableau, PowerBI, SQL, and Data Science libraries. Enthusiastic learner with various additional courses in Statistics and Data Science.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Data Analytics
- ✓ Advanced English
- ✓ PowerBI

- ✓ Machine Learning
- Python
- Data Science Libs

✓ ETL

✓ SQL

(Pandas, Seaborn, MatPlotLib e SKLearn)

- Data Visualization
- ✓ Tableau

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Amazon

BI Intern | June, 2022 - Present

- Data Analysis with Python
- Development and maintenance of tableau dashboards
- · Text Classification using LLMs through AWS Cloud.
- Query development using SQL

Mercedes-Benz do Brasil

Data Analytics Intern | March, 2021 - June, 2022

- · Data Analysis with Python
- · Deep dive analysis using Machine Learning
- Development and maintenance of PowerBI dashboards.
- Process automations using Python

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Faculdade Engenheiro Salvador Arena

Computer engineering | January, 2020 - December, 2024

- Undergraduate Research Program LLMs + IOT
- Course presentation Machine Learning with Python

ETEC Lauro Gomes

Technical Course in Mechatronics | January, 2017 - December, 2019

- Automated forklift controlled by smartphone.
- Musical presentations

ADDITIONAL COURSES

MITx - Micromasters in Statistics and Data Science (Doing)

DeepLearning.Al - Sequences, Time Series and Prediction

AWS - Certified Cloud Practitioner

Alura - Machine Learning

Alura - Data Science

LANGUAGES